你以为你所知道,关于他的传言是真的吗？
You think you know the truth about him?
你一无所知
You know nothing.
他的父亲是宙斯
His father was Zeus. The Zeus.
众神之王
King of the gods.
他的母亲,阿尔克墨涅，一个凡人的女人
His mother, Alcmene, a mortal woman.
他们生下了一个男孩
Together, they had a boy.
半人
Half human,
半神
half god.
但宙斯的皇后赫拉,将这个孽种视为一种侮辱
But Zeus' queen, Hera, saw this bastard child as an insult,
不断的提醒她丈夫的不忠
a living reminder of her husband's infidelity.
他母亲阿尔克墨将他取名为男孩海里克斯
Alcmene named the boy Hercules, which means "glory of Hera,"
意思是“赫拉的荣耀”
which means "glory of Hera,"
但这还是不能安抚皇后
but this failed to appease the goddess.
皇后希望他死
She wanted him dead.
幸运的是他如同他的父亲
Luckily, he took after his father.
一旦他到了成年
Once he reached manhood,
神吩咐他执行十二劳动
the gods commanded him to perform Twelve Labors,
十二危险任务
twelve dangerous missions.
如果他完成了并存活下来
If he completed them all and survived,
赫拉同意最后让他平静的生活
Hera agreed to finally let him live in peace.
他跟九头蛇搏斗！
He fought the Lernean Hydra!
与大野猪搏斗！
He battled the Erymanthean Boar!
但他最大的挑战是尼米亚猛狮
But his greatest Labor was the Nemean Lion.
这不是普通的野兽
This was no ordinary beast.
它隐藏如此隐密,没有武器可以伤害它
It had a hide so tough,no weapon could penetrate it.
但即使这样,怪物还是不敌宙斯的儿子
But even this monster was no match for the son of Zeus.
都是鬼扯
What a load of crap!
每一个字都是真的
Every word is true.
你知道我的想法吗？
You know what I think?
你的这个朋友根本不存在
This friend of yours doesn't even exist.
你尽管笑吧
Laugh all you want.
当他来了时你们最好小心点，他鄙视海盗
He's coming. And be warned, Gryza, he despises pirates.
马其顿一直对我们好
Macedonia has been good to us.
大量的村庄等待着我们去掠夺
Plenty of villages ripe for pillaging.
我们在这里留下
We are here to stay.
解决他
Finish him.
你越挣扎,你越快落下
The more you struggle,the faster you drop。
的确你们真的很强大.我…
Indeed, your fleet is strong. I...
然而，我只是想要解释我刚刚很粗鲁地打断
Yet, as I was about to explain before I was so rudely interrupted,
复仇女神的狮子也很强劲
the Nemean Lion was strong, too.
然而，他还是摧毁了它
Yet, he still destroyed it.
而不是一把剑或矛或箭头，都不是！
And not with a sword or a spear or arrows. No!
我只用双手就把他宰了！
I did it with my bare hands!
如同他们所说
Or so they say.
海克力士
Hercules.
这就是你所有的战士吗？
Is this all the men you have?
我们有40人你只有一个
There's 40 of us. One of you.
这里的国王给我黄金要我处理你
The king of this land has offered me gold to dispose of you.
所以离开，或死亡
So leave, or die.
我都能得到报酬
I get paid either way.
让他流血
Make him bleed.
一棍就撂倒五个人
Five men with a single blow.
你仍然认为你可以摧毁宙斯的儿子吗？
Still think you can destroy the son of Zeus?
给我他的头！
Bring me his head!
似乎他们需要更多证明，奥托吕科斯
Seems they need more convincing, Autolycus.
这就是我们在这里的原因
That's why we're here.
亚特兰大
Atalanta.
安菲阿拉奥斯
Amphiaraus.
愿宙斯原谅你
May Zeus forgive you.
堤丢斯
Tydeus?
去死吧，海克力士！
Die, Hercules!
啊，干的好
Ah, good man.
快点！
Hurry!
快点！叔叔！
Hurry! Uncle!
叔叔，快点！
Uncle, hurry!
快点！快点！
Hurry! Hurry!
差一点就...叔叔…
Any longer, Uncle...
女孩都是到最后才被拯救的
And the girls would finally be safe from your attentions.
你们其他人可以走了
The rest of you may go.
不是你
But not you.Thirteen,
14、15、16日
17、18、19、20 可真有趣啊
17、18、19、20 That was fun.
二十个海盗,一个头两个金币
Twenty pirates at two gold pieces a head,
减去一个无头的让我们来看看
minus the headless ones. Let's see.
还不错的夜晚
Not a bad night.
你看到海盗跑了吗？我的故事软化他们的决心
You see how the pirates ran? My story softened their resolve.
他们的决心必须被攻破
Their resolve must be broken, Iolaus.
当你传播海克力士的传奇
When you spread the legend of Hercules, make it bigger, scarier.
使它更大，可怕
The more
他们相信赫拉克勒斯是真正宙斯的儿子
they believe Hercules is truly the son of Zeus
越不可能他们战斗
the less likely they are to fight.
哦！
Oh!
啊
Aye.
- 安菲阿拉奥斯？- 嗯？
- Amphiaraus? - Mmm?
想加入我们吗？
Care to join us here on Earth?
一只狮子和一只乌鸦诡异的联盟在一起,在跟海洋上的尸体考验
A lion and a crow in strange alliance, fighting across a sea of corpses.
如果你要使用这些草药,安菲阿拉奥斯，至少也要分享吧
If you're going to use those herbs, Amphiaraus, at least share.
嗯？
Huh?
再坚持一下！再坚持一下！再坚持一下！再坚持一下！
Hold it! Hold it!Hold it! Hold it!
赢了！
Fight it!
继续练习吧，孩子！
Keep practicing, boys!
下一个是谁？你吗？你吗？
So who's next? You? You?
啊
Ah!
这是一个美丽的景像
That's a pretty sight.
一个发薪日，奥托吕科斯.这就是我们需要的
One more payday, Autolycus, that's all we need.
然后我们去过像我的国王一样的生活
Then we get to live like the kings we've served.
或简单生活
Or live simply.
你还在梦想你的野人岛？
You still dreaming of barbarian lands?
过了爱琴海在黑海的海岸
Beyond the Aegean.At the shores of the Black Sea.
那里就是我将度过我孤独余生的地方
That is where I will live out the rest of my days in solitude.
无聊，如果你问我
Boring, if you ask me.
也许是这样，奥托吕科斯
Maybe so, Autolycus.
我永远不会找到和平.除非我尽可能的远离
But I'll never find peace unless I move as far away as possible.
那堤丢斯怎么办？
What of Tydeus?
没有你，以他愤怒的脾气. 我担心他可能会成为一个什么样的人
Without you to temper his rage, I fear what he may become.
堤丢斯将和我一起离开
Tydeus will go with me.
文明对我们来说已经太过文明了
Civilization has become too civilized for us.
叔叔！
Uncle!
加入我们的行列,姑娘们都在热切欢迎你
Join us. The girls are eager to welcome you.
你看，我就说我认识海克力士
See? I told you I knew Hercules.
你是他的仆人吗？
Are you his servant?
我是他的侄子
I'm his nephew.
真的是你吗？
Are you, really?
我告诉的.赫拉克勒斯的十二劳动
I tell of Hercules' Twelve Labors,
像复仇女神的狮子.赫斯帕里得斯的苹果
like the Nemean Lion,
希波吕忒的皮带
the Apples of the Hesperides,
丰满的裸体亚马逊女战士和令人兴奋的束缚
the Belt of Hippolyta with its buxom naked Amazons and exciting bondage.
我使他…当他讲到我们其余战斗的同时
I immortalize him... - He talks, while the rest of us fight.
我真怀疑你跟海克力士有着相同的血源
It is a wonder you share the same blood as Hercules.
玩得开心
Have fun.
女士们
- Ladies. - Oh...
你找海克力士干嘛？
What do you want with Hercules?
我有话跟他说，不是你
My words are for him, not you.
亚特兰大，没关系
Atalanta, it's all right.
你真是一个难找的人啊
You certainly are a hard man to find.
也许我不希望任何人都能找到我
Maybe I don't want anyone to find me.
我不是任何人
I'm not just anyone.
我的名字叫爱吉你亚.科蒂国王的女儿
My name is Ergenia, daughter to Lord Cotys.
你父亲是最幸运的,有这样一个美丽的继承人
Your father is most fortunate to have such a beautiful heir.
我的父亲是最不幸的
My father is most unfortunate.
他要对抗一个军阀，瑞社
He battles a warlord, Rhesus.
我们的土地被内战撕裂
Our land is torn by civil war.
每一天，村庄破坏，农作物被毁,无辜被屠宰
Every day,villages are destroyed, crops ruined,innocents slaughtered.
我们都有问题
We all have problems.
好吧，也许我可以使你相信,我们的问题就是你的问题
Well, perhaps I can convince you to make our problems your own.
不幸的是，我的夫人
Unfortunately, My Lady,
赫拉克勒斯是受雇于迪奥尼索司
Hercules is fully committed till the Feast of Dionysus.
然而，我们可以
We could, however,
提前是你提供合适的价格
advance you to the front of the line, for the right price.
嗯
Hmm.
我认为英雄为荣耀而战
I thought heroes, fight for glory.
但雇佣兵为金牌而战
But mercenaries fight for gold.
科蒂勋爵是一个富有的人
Lord Cotys is a rich man.
我已经喜欢他了
I like him already.
如果你同意帮助他.他将支付你相同重量的金子
If you agree to aid him, he will pay your weight in gold.
吃起来
Eat up.
“狮子和乌鸦,奇怪的联盟”
"A lion and crow in strange alliance."
告诉你了
Told you.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
这是很高兴见到你安全，夫人
It is good to see you safe, My Lady.
这场战争每天造成了很多牺牲者,我们一直担心你，夫人
This war claims more victims every day. We were concerned, My Lady.
谢谢你，史特寇将军,我受到很好的保护
Thank you, General Sitacles.I was well protected.
啊
Ah.
强大的海克力士,见到你是我的荣幸
The mighty Hercules. An honor
但是并没有如我所预期的荣幸
Though not quite as big an honor as I expected.
将军，去告诉我的父亲,海克力士在这里
General, go tell my father Hercules is here.
叔叔吗？赫拉让人印像深刻
Uncle? Hera. Impressive.
它应该是
It's meant to be.
花了五年和一千人建立了神庙
It took five years and a thousand men to build her temple.
赫拉是家喻户晓的色雷斯的女神
Hera is the patron goddess of Thrace.
每个人都知道这个传说,赫拉如何企图摧毁海克力士
Everyone knows the legend, how Hera seeks to destroy Hercules.
也许正确的原因可能最终和解
Perhaps the right cause might finally reconcile you.
妈妈！
Mother!
艾利斯
Arius.
你是海克力士——是对的
- You're Hercules. - That's right.
我的名字叫艾利斯,我知道你所有的考验
My name is Arius. I know all your Labors by heart.
你只用了一击就杀了巨人吉里昂
You killed the giant Geryon with a single blow,
一个晚上解决了一群恶棍
cleaned the Augean stables in one night.
海克力士可能是累了
Hercules is probably tired.
狮子的考验和恶魔的考验
And the Labor of the Hide,and the Labor of the Mares.
够了，艾利斯 过来
That's enough, Arius. Come along.
远离他
Stay away from him.
暴力的人，会吸引暴力
Men who deal in violence attract violence.
但他的海克力士,他不是凡人他是最伟大的！
But he's Hercules. He's no mere mortal. He's the greatest!
科蒂国王现在就见到你
Lord Cotys will see you now.
你有没有晋见过皇室.海克力士？
Have you ever met royalty, Hercules?
一次或两次
Once or twice.
父亲
Father!
墨伽拉
Megara.
欢迎回家，我的爱
Welcome home, my love.
海克力士！
Hercules!
每当我在这里,我总在想极乐世界必须看起来就像这样
Whenever I'm here, I imagine this is what Elysium must look like.
好，像我们这样的人能够
Well, men like us have
在这个世界上建造我们自己的天堂
the means to create our own paradise on Earth.
看
Look.
宏伟的，不是吗？
Magnificent, aren't they?
好了，不让我们再挂心我们是否安全的 远离怪物九头蛇？
Well, do not keep us in suspense. Are we safe from the monster Hydra?
九头蛇的脑袋,陛下
The Hydra's heads, Your Majesty.
蛇的面具
The masks of serpents.
难怪人民会认为他们是怪物
No wonder men thought they were monsters.
你为了你的国家,做了一个重大的贡献来吧
You've done your sovereign a great service. Come.
让人民见见他们的英雄
Let the people have their hero.
大家欢呼吧，国王欧律斯透斯
All hail King Eurystheus.
和强大的雅典守护者
And the mighty protector of Athens,
海克力士！
Hercules!
海克力士！海克力士！海克力士！
Hercules! Hercules! Hercules!
一个凡人面对这样的崇拜可能会认为自己是上帝
A man faced with such adoration might be tempted to think himself a god.
我只想当个平凡的丈夫和父亲
I only want to be a husband and a father.
科蒂国王在等你
Lord Cotys awaits.
海克力士
Hercules.
欢迎
Welcome.
多么光荣接见这样一个传奇
An honor to host such a legend.
科蒂国王
Lord Cotys.
但是传说中你都是单独战斗
But in legend, you fight alone.
如果没有我的伙伴,我的名声将不存在
My reputation would not exist without my comrades.
奥托吕科斯斯巴达
Autolycus of Sparta.
堤丢斯底比斯
Tydeus of Thebes.
塞西亚的亚特兰大
Atalanta of Scythia.
依的雅典
Iolaus of Athens.
和安菲阿拉奥斯阿哥斯
And Amphiaraus of Argos.
安菲阿拉奥斯？
Amphiaraus?
阿哥斯的著名的预言家
The famed seer of Argos.
据说你可以看到你自己的死亡
It is said you have glimpsed your own death,
所以你每个战役战斗你都预知了你的死期还未到
so you fight each battle knowing that it is not yet your time to die.
你还能预知其他的未来吗？
What else can you tell of the future?
只有唯一的神能预见能被预知的未来
Only what the gods see fit to reveal.
的确，真是羞愧
A shame.
能预知这场战争的结果必须要有极大的天赋
It would have been a great gift to know the outcome of this war.
神有时真是令人沮丧啊,科蒂国王
The gods can be frustrating sometimes, Lord Cotys.
没有不尊重的意思， 我担心未来的任务可能不是适合于一个女人
With respect, I fear that the task ahead might not be suitable for a woman,
即使她是一个亚马逊女战士
even if she is an Amazon warrior.
我认错
I stand corrected.
当昔日的国王，建造了这座城堡
When the kings of yesteryear built this citadel,
原本是想成为色雷斯的最高王位
it was intended as the high seat of all Thrace.
但现在色雷斯已经分裂
But now Thrace is divided.
这场战争已耗尽我们的军队
This war has depleted our forces.
我们什么都没留下，只剩农民和商人来补充我们的军队
We're left with nothing but farmers and merchants to replenish our army.
这需要我们每一个人对抗瑞社
It takes every one of us to resist Rhesus.
人民认为他无法被一个凡人杀死
People think that he cannot be killed by an ordinary mortal.
上帝能杀他
Only by a god.
瑞社是一个魔法师
Rhesus is a sorcerer.
他的咒语迷惑人弯曲他的意志
His magic words confuse men,bend them to his will.
他领导一群怪物 半人马，一半人类一半马
He leads an army of monsters,half horse, half human.
半人马？
Centaurs?
你真的见过他们吗？他们已经见过
You've actually seen them? They have been seen.
来，海克力士
Come, Hercules.
让我展是给你看瑞社所带给我们的痛苦
Let me show you what misery Rhesus has brought us.
每个星期，更多的难民到达,寻求我的保护
Every week, more refugees arrive seeking my protection,
他们中的大多数经历了瑞社的残害,流血，受伤或被伤烧的
most of them covered in blood,crippled or burnt by Rhesus' men.
我害怕日子没有能再好转的一天,直到你的到来
I feared nothing could ever be good again, till you arrived.
我只是一个雇佣兵为金币而战
I'm just a mercenary fighting for gold.
我们如何看待自己产生的后果很小
How we view ourselves is of little consequence.
但是别人如何认为我们是更重要的
How others perceive us is important.
和你的名字，不管你喜不喜欢
And your name, like it or not,
那是一个号召
is a rallying cry.
我见过太多的事实,去相信传说，我不是一个人
I have seen too much reality to trust in legends, and I am not alone.
已经没有人有信心了
Nobody has any faith anymore.
人民需要一个英雄;他们需要有人崇拜
The people need a hero.They need someone to look up to.
我的儿子相信你
My son believes in you.
给我们带来和平
Bring us peace, and...
和我将,我也相信你
I will believe in you, too.
我相信这些都是很好的人
I'm convinced these are good people.
我明白了，谁更有说服力,科蒂还是他的女儿？
I see. And who's more convincing,Cotys or his daughter?
地球上所有的黄金还不如一对乳房，让人信服
All the gold on Earth is not as convincing as a pair of breasts.
也许，但黄金没有年龄
Maybe, but gold never ages.
这就是为什么,我得到了他们两倍的价格
Which is why I got them to double our price.
两倍重量的金子？好
Double your weight in gold? Well done.
安菲阿拉奥斯？
Amphiaraus?
如果它是宙斯的旨意
If it be the will of Zeus.
什么样的标题会让我们的敌人听起来更害怕
Which title sounds more terrifying to our enemies? "Hercules: Savior of Thrace"
“海克力士，色雷斯的救世主”或“海克力士，一个传奇诞生”？
or "Hercules: A Legend is Born"?
两个听起来都很无聊
Both sound terrifyingly boring.
我们应该做什么呢?一群农民吗？
What are we supposed to do with an army of farmers?
培训他们
Train them.
哦，可恶
Oh, shit.
在战争中，有一件事比死亡更重要
In war, there is one thing more important than killing.
幸存的
Surviving.
我的同伴，我将向您展示如何保持活着
My companions and I will show you how to stay alive,
所以，你可能回家 回到你农场的一天
so that you may return home to your farms someday.
奥托吕科斯
Autolycus.
盾墙！阵式！
Shield wall! Form！
尸体！每一个一个的你！
Corpses! Every last one of you!
因为你的盾墙是弱
Because your shield wall was weak.
死了
Dead.
非常死
Very dead.
士兵
Soldier,
许多的生命取决于你
many lives depend on you.
攻击时锁你的脚在地上
When attacked, lock your feet in the ground.
你明白吗？
You understand?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
当一个盾墙强
When a shield wall is strong,
没有什么能打败它！
nothing can ever defeat it!
你必须学习共同努力，反应在一起
You must learn to work together,react together.
当你这样做了，每个人将成为一个链接链
When you do, each individual will become a link in a chain
这将是比铁更坚固
that will be stronger than iron.
我希望敌人有幽默感
I hope the enemy has a sense of humor.
是的，今天的课程,如何不刺到自己！
Right. Today's lesson, how not to stab yourselves！
当务之急，是我们现在攻击，国王有这种机会
It is imperative that we strike now,My Lord, given this opportunity.
啊你就在那里！
Ah! There you are!
海克力士，我的斥侯兵带来了好消息,瑞社在移动
Hercules, my scouts have brought news. Rhesus is on the move.
弓箭手从他们的弓射的箭如同闪电一般
Archers who shoot lightning from their bows.
和步兵4000，他们被迷惑
And infantry 4,000-strong,their minds bewitched.
恶魔与他们同行
Demons march with them.
所以现在我们在跟恶魔战斗
So now we're fighting demons.
怪物你应该不陌生,我听说你遇到，海克力士
No stranger than the monsters I hear you faced, Hercules.
我的国王，瑞社正准备攻击卑斯
My Lord, Rhesus is preparing to attack Bessi lands.
他将在在六天到达
He will be on them within six days.
如果卑斯被攻下，我们就是下一个,除非我们拦截他
If the Bessi fall, we're next.Unless we intercept him.
你的军队需要几周训练,才能准备就绪
Your men need weeks, if not months,of training before they're ready.
卑斯是凶猛但原始的部落
The Bessi are a fierce but primitive tribe.
如果我们不保护他们,将会是一场血腥屠杀
If we do not protect them,then there will be a bloodbath.
以未经训练的军队面对瑞社
Face Rhesus with an untrained army
你可能失去远远超过一个战斗
and you risk losing far more than a single battle.
我的主，瑞社即将来临,我会用生命跟他决战
My Lord, Rhesus is coming.I vouch my life on it.
瑞社活的时间越长
The longer Rhesus lives,
村庄就越被烧毁和更多无辜的人将会死亡
the more villages will be burnt and the more innocents will be killed.
集合你的军队,我们明天出发
Assemble your men. We march tomorrow.
海克力士,众神给我们一份礼物
Hercules, the gods have offered us a gift.
我们不能浪费它
We must not squander it.
你的神要和我们一起战斗吗？
Are your gods going to be fighting with us?
不
No.
但是宙斯的儿子会
The son of Zeus will.
我看到了你,看在海克力士
I've seen how you watch over Hercules.
请告诉我
Tell me,
是怎样一个女人
how did a woman,
美丽的女人
beautiful woman,
会跟这些勇士？
fall in with these hardened men?
杀手？一起同行
Killers?
宙斯的儿子需要一个女人的保护吗？
Son of Zeus need a woman's protection?
我不保护他
I don't protect him.
我保护你避免他伤害你
I protect you from him.
嗯
Hmm.
将军，现在，也许你该去看看你的军队
General, from now on, maybe you should favor the company of your men.
你抢了他的刀？
He pulled a knife?
那只是一把小刀
It was only a small prick.
——啊
你母亲告诉你应该保持距离,你应该要听话
Your mother told you to stay away. You should listen.
他怎么了？
What's wrong with him?
堤丢斯是我的最忠诚的战士
Tydeus is my most loyal warrior.
他出生在战争
He was born in war.
当我发现他时跟人类相比他更像是野兽
When I found him, he was more animal than human.
他从不谈论他所看到的一切
He never speaks of what he saw.
他从不谈论
He never speaks at all.
但他每天晚上都要在经历他所经历的
But he relives it every night.
来了
Come.
让我们去找你母亲
Let's find your mother.
当我长大了,我想成为像你这样的大英雄
When I grow up, I want to be a great hero like you.
像我？没有英雄比海克力士更伟大
Like me?    No hero is greater than Hercules.
我知道你所有的考验
I know all your Labors.
克利特岛公牛的七天七夜对决
Like the Cretan Bull, you wrestled it for seven days，and seven nights.
嗯，这有点夸大了
Uh, that's a bit exaggerated.
用你的武器打了他49下,也许没那么多下
And struck it 49 times with your club.Maybe not quite that many.
直到倒地而死和克里特岛得救了 这是我最喜欢的考验
Until it fell dead and Crete was saved.It's my favorite Labor.
还有希波吕忒女王的腰带，
Also Queen Hippolyta's Belt,
以其丰满的亚马逊女战士和令人兴奋的束缚
with it's buxom Amazons and exciting bondage.
- 你知道那是什么意思吗？ - 不知道
- Do you even know what that means?  - No.
妈妈  艾利斯
- Mother.  - Arius.
你应该在床上
You're supposed to be in bed.
你为什么在医务所？
Why are you in the hospice?
我的母亲医治人们的生命
My mother saves people's lives.
我们的许多医生在战斗中丧生
Many of our physicians were killed during battle.
所以，出于必要我自学治疗的技术
So, out of necessity, I taught myself the art of healing.
如果我可以像你一样
If I could be like you,
我将保护所有的色雷斯和没有人会受伤
I would protect all of Thrace and no one would ever get hurt.
那
Here.
我要把这个送给别人
I was going to give this to someone else,
但是我一直没机会
but I never got the chance.
只有一个英雄可以穿戴
Only a hero may wear this.
但是要成为一个英雄,你必须变得强壮
But to become a hero,you must grow strong.
这是复仇女神的狮子的牙齿吗？
Is this the Nemean Lion's tooth?
- 是 - 谢谢
- It is. - Thank you.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
晚安，各位
Good night.
晚安，海克力士
Good night, Hercules.
没有恐惧
Have no fear.
如果你是因为正义的理由服役而捐躯 你的灵魂将会前往天堂，
If you fall in the service of a just cause, your souls will go to Elysium,
他们将永远住在哪里在英雄的庇荫下，
where they will dwell forever among the shades of heroes,
如同忒修斯
like Theseus.
奥德修斯！
Odysseus!
和伟大的阿奇里斯一般
And the great Achilles.
或者如果你够幸运,你会去地狱，跟所有的有趣的人做伴
Or if you're lucky, you'll go to Hades,where all the fun people are.
依
Iolaus.
你跟在科蒂国王旁边,这样比较安全
Your place is beside Lord Cotys, where it's safe.
我已经做了很多的思想准备，我真的觉得,我准备好可以战斗了
I've been giving it a lot of thought,and I really feel I'm ready to fight.
你是一个讲故事的人,不是一个战士
You're a storyteller, not a warrior.
我们有着相同的血液
We share the same blood.
所以我才不希望看到它流出,上战车
And I will not see it shed. Chariot.
现在
Now.
色雷斯人
Thracians,
盾墙是你的家,你的住所
the shield wall is your home. Your shelter.
当你睡觉时,墙上是你的毯子
When you sleep,the wall is your blanket.
当你打架,墙上是你的护甲
When you fight,the wall is your armor.
盾墙将永远不会被打破,只要你的身体还有呼吸
The shield wall will never break formation as long as there is breath in your body.
记住这些话
Remember these words,
你会品尝胜利
and you will taste victory.
军队前进！
Move the army out!Move out!
停止！
Halt!
Halt!Halt!
停止！
我们太迟了
We are too late.
瑞社已经在这里
Rhesus,has already been here.
下车,我们将步行去
Leave the chariots.We'll go down on foot.
狮子和乌鸦,交错一整区的尸体
The lion and crow cross,a field of corpses.
我讨厌每次都被我说中
I hate being right all the time.
停止
Halt.
停止！
Halt!Halt!
这个头是腐烂的
This head is rotting.
至少一个星期了
A week old, at least.
然而，其中的一些身体是新鲜的
Yet some of these bodies are fresh.
叔叔！
Uncle!
我们走进一个陷阱
And we've walked into a trap.
盾墙！单一方阵！保护主科蒂！ 依，走吧！
Shield wall! Form a single square!Protect Lord Cotys! Iolaus, go!
盾墙！
Shield wall!
我们来这里是来帮助他们,他们为什么攻击？
We're here to help them.Why are they attacking?
这是瑞社干的好事
This is Rhesus' doing.
他们说他的法术有覆盖人类的思想的力量
They say his spells have the power to cloud minds.
使伙伴互相攻击
Turn comrades against each other.
国王的卫队，包围住科蒂国王！
King's guards, around Lord Cotys!
安菲阿拉奥斯.我们会在这场战役中死去吗？
Amphiaraus, do we die in this battle?
我的时间还没有来.不确定你的
My time's not come yet.Not sure about yours.
这是令人欣慰的
That's comforting.
我认为他想要一个挑战
I think he wants a challenge.
赫拉克里斯的拳头曾经在在九头蛇的血液中落下！
Hercules' fists have been dipped in the blood of the Hydra!
总是让人致命！
Lethal to anyone but him!
看！
Watch!
你看到了吗？
Did you see that?
上帝站在我们这一边！
The gods fight on our side!
海克力士！海克力士！海克力士！
Hercules! Hercules! Hercules!
海克力士！海克力士！
Hercules! Hercules!
海克力士！海克力士！海克力士！
Hercules! Hercules! Hercules!
战斗位置！
Battle position!
阿耳特弥斯女神，如果我倒下.让我…
Lady Artemis, if I am to fall,let me be judged...
坚守位置！
Stand fast!
坚守你的位置！
Hold your position!
不退让！
Do not yield!
不撤退！保持盾墙！
No retreat! Stay in the wall!
坚守阵线！
Hold the lines!
不屈服！
Do not yield!
保护科蒂王！
Defend Lord Cotys!
墙被打破了！
The wall has been breached!
密封的盾墙！保护主科蒂！
Seal up the shield wall! Defend Lord Cotys!
鞭子！
Whip!
海克力士！
Hercules!
去驾战车！
Bring the chariots!
保护王！
Defend your Lord!
不！
No!
推进！
Advance!
前进！
让路！
Make way!
瑞社在哪里？
Where is Rhesus?
科蒂王
Lord Cotys.
我们来到这里.保存这个村，
We came here to save this village,
但是，不，他们杀了我一半的军队
but, no, they killed half my army.
瑞社
Rhesus.
这都是他做的
This is all his doing.
和你的失误
And yours.
我警告你
I warned you.
你的男人是勇敢的.但未经训练的，准备战斗
Your men are brave,but untrained, unprepared for battle.
给我时间训练他们成为战士
Give me time to make warriors.
很好
Very well.
掩盖好，不能让你在忠诚的军队看见你像凡人一样流血
Cover up, before your loyal army sees you bleed like a mortal.
菲尼亚斯
Phineas.
你为你的生命抗辩
You plead your life.
我很乐意交出我的生命
And I gladly offer it.
我没有看到这个陷阱
I failed to see this trap.
是我的错！又一个斥侯兵
The fault is mine!Spare the other scouts.
史蒂克将军
General Sitacles.
我认为我们今天已经失去了足够的战士，不是吗？
I think we've lost enough men for the day, don't you?
但为了避免未来的误解
But just to avoid future misunderstandings,
我将负责从现在开始担任你的斥侯兵
I'll be taking charge of your scouts from now on.
清楚了吗？
Is that clear?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
再犯一次错误.我将自己结束你的生命
Another mistake, I'll end you myself.
帮你涂抹一种薄荷药膏;洋甘菊和粘土用来治疗伤口
I'm applying a salve of mint,chamomile and clay to seal the wound.
这是从岩石提取治疗疼痛的一个强大的镇静剂
This is extract of lithops for the pain, a powerful sedative.
他可以安抚你它，可能有某些副作用
It should rest you after consuming it.It may have certain side effects.
我不需要它
I don't need it.
啊，原谅我，我忘记了。凡人不能伤害海克力士
Ah, forgive me, I forgot.No mortal can harm Hercules.
嗯，你的隐藏的狮子不也是坚不可摧的吗？
And, uh, your lion's hide is indestructible?
喝酒，宙斯的儿子
Drink, son of Zeus.
艾利斯的父亲也是一样的，他不信任药物
Arius' father was the same,he distrusted medicines.
他现在在哪里？
Where is he now?
被神带走了。在我儿子出生前
Taken by the gods before my son was born.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我从来没见过我的父亲
I never knew my father.
嗯，他一定是非常，非常强大
Well, he must have been very, very strong.
告诉我关于艾利斯
Tell me about Arius.
哦他是一个好男孩
Oh. He's a good boy.
有一天 他将成为一个好国王
And someday, he will make a fine king
你有孩子吗？
Do you have any children?
他们住在雅典吗？
Do they live in Athens?
谢谢你的关心
Thank you for your care.
镇静剂可以帮助你休息
The sedative will help you rest.
你怎么可以做这样一个可怕的事情？
How could you do such a terrible thing?
根据法律规定，我应该处决你，
By law, I should execute you,
但我相信一个更合适的惩罚会让你生不如死
but I believe a more fitting punishment would be to let you live.
所以你可以走在折磨的世界里，受尽鬼魂的围绕
So you can walk the earth in torment, haunted by the knowledge
让你为你爱的人死亡负责
that you alone are responsible for the death of your loved ones.
伟大的海克力士
The great Hercules.
手永远染上无辜人的血
Hands forever stained with innocent blood.
出去，你这怪物
Get out, you monster.
出去！
Get out!
不！
No!
又再一次发生，不是吗，嗯？
It happened again, didn't it, hmm?
又一个地狱守门兽的幻觉三个头的地狱看门地狱兽吗？
Another vision of Cerberus,the three-headed beast of Hades?
神给你的东西，他们不希望与别人分享
The gods show you things they don't share with others.
只有一个词形容：疯狂
There's a word for that. Madness.
当我们在雅典，
When we were driven from Athens,I consulted the Oracle of Delphi...
以你的名义我占卜了特尔菲的甲骨文
on your behalf.
你还记得她的预言吗？
Do you remember her prophecy?
“海克力士必须完成剩下未完成的考验”
"Hercules must finish the Labor that remains unfinished."
海克力士，那是什么？
And what is that, Hercules?
面对萦绕在你周围的野兽只有这样你找到和平
Confront the beast that haunts you.Only then will you find peace.
我说的都来自我的经验
I speak from experience.
无论你跑多远，无论你走多快，野兽都会跟随
No matter how far you run, no matter how fast you go,the beast will follow.
人不能逃避自己的命运
Man cannot escape his fate.
还有多余的位置吗？
Room for one more in your company?
有女性的作伴这将是一种荣幸
It'd be a pleasure having female companionship for a change.
亚特兰大不计数，没有进攻
Atalanta doesn't quite count.No offense.
要是你的男子气概跟你的舌头一样
If only your manhood was as long as your tongue.
两者都满意在不同情况下
Both can satisfy in different ways.
你是一个著名的说书人，依跟我说一个故事
You're a famed storyteller, Iolaus.Grace me with a story.
任何特定的主题，我的夫人吗？
Any particular subject, My Lady?
谋杀，一个女人的和她的三个孩子
Murder, of a woman and her three children.
是真的吗？海克力士屠杀自己的家庭吗？
Is it true? Did Hercules slaughter his own family？
- 谁这样说吗？ - 哦，士兵交谈
- Who said so? - Oh, soldiers talk.
他们说如果海克力士回到雅典
They say if Hercules ever returns to Athens,
国王欧律斯透斯将会将他处死
King Eurystheus will have him executed.
海克力士完成了他的考验和回家 但赫拉…
Hercules had completed his Labors and returned home. But Hera...
不要神话我想要真相
No myths. I want the truth.
没有人知道真相
No one knows the truth.
不肯定的
Not for sure.
我们发现海克力士他的妻子墨伽拉和孩子死了
We found Hercules alone. His wife, Megara and the children, dead.
他什么也不记得
He remembers nothing.
你相信他是无辜的吗？
Do you believe he is innocent?
我们一起长大，都是孤儿，在雅典的街道中努力生存
We grew up together, both orphans,trying to survive in the streets of Athens.
在军队中我们是一家人,我们互相照顾
We found a home in the army.Looked out for each other.
海克力士的力量让他与众不同
Hercules' strength set him apart.
雅典的国王开始在所有最危险的任务交给他
Kings of Athens started to send him on all the most dangerous missions.
十二考验
The Twelve Labors.
他带我和他在一起
And he took me with him.
战斗在他身边
To fight by his side.
和每一个任务,我们的人数增加
And with each mission, our numbers grew.
塞西亚，亚马逊王国 皇室家族被暗杀
Scythia, the Amazon kingdom where the royal family had been assassinated.
我的家人已经不见了,每个人都走了
My family was gone.Everyone was gone.
海克力士帮助我报复他们的谋杀
Hercules helped me avenge their murder.
他成了我的战友
He became my brother-in-arms.
底比斯城的尸体
Thebes, the city of corpses,
我们发现一个孩子
where we found a single child,
还活着
still alive.
海克力士在当时救了堤丢斯
Hercules took Tydeus in
而其他人只把他当成野生动物一般
when everyone else saw nothing but a wild animal.
你知道谣言传播,一个传奇的发生
You know how a rumor spreads.How a legend grows.
海克力士的行为,如此令人难以置信的
Hercules' deeds were so incredible,
那不可能是一个凡人的表现
they could not possibly have been performed by a mere mortal.
所以我们成为了伙伴
So we played along.
我们引导人们去认为海克力士是宙斯的儿子，这样很好
We encourage people to think Hercules was the son of Zeus. It's good.
可以让敌人恐惧
Scares the enemy.
依的帮助
Iolaus helps.
他言词很厉害
He talks nice.
你们是忠诚的朋友
You're very loyal friends.
你回避我的问题
You're avoiding my question.
海克力士是一个战士
Hercules is a warrior.
自然有一些事情困扰着战士
And there is something that haunts warriors.
它可以扰乱他们的想法
It can cloud their minds.
我们叫它血的愤怒
We call it the Blood Rage.
这愤怒折磨海克力士
This rage afflicted Hercules.
他让我发誓要让世界远离他
He made me vow to keep the world away from him.
为了确保他会不会再伤害无辜
To make sure that he would never harm innocents again.
而且，夫人，是事实
And that, My Lady, is the truth.
真相
The truth,
无论真相如何
whatever the truth,
他所爱的人的死亡一直萦绕着海克力士
the death of his loved ones haunts Hercules.
只有神能帮助他
Only the gods can help him,
如果他听的进去
if he listens.
过来！围过来，色雷斯的士兵，看哪
Come! Gather around,soldiers of Thrace, and behold,
当海克力士给众神下了一个订单,即使众神也必须服从
when Hercules gives an order,even the gods listen.
宙斯的铁匠大师
Zeus' master ironsmith,
使用你们城堡的冶炼厂
using the forges of your own citadel,
铸造了这些神圣的武器 这将使你永远立于不败之地
has crafted these divine weapons that will make you invincible.
盾牌是钢铁锻造而成的
As steel is hewn into shields,
所以，你也会被锻造成为战士
so, too, will you be hewn into warriors.
你应该要带着海克力士的盾牌！
You shall carry the shield of Hercules!
非常的轻
It's lighter.
注入了史蒂佛林鸟兽的灵魂
Infused with the souls of Stymphalian birds
从赫拉克里斯的第6个考验的战利品！
from Hercules' sixth Labor!
鸟的灵魂吗？这是要如何使用的？
Spirits of birds?How does that work, exactly?
嗯，如同鸟类飞行一般，
Well, much as birds take flight, so,
同样，这些是盾牌.它的纤维比空气轻，另外这里
too, are these shields lighter than air.It's in the fibers. Here.
试穿海克力士的头盔
Try on the helmet of Hercules.
它覆盖了我整个脸
It covers my whole face.
当他打败了恶魔吉里昂,在海克力士的头盔之后所锻造
Forged after Hercules' very own helmet,when he defeated the demon Geryon.
你确定这不是你的胡说八道，吓死吉里昂的吗？
You sure it wasn't your horseshit that frightened Geryon to death?
嗯？
Mmm?
史蒂克将军
General Sitacles,
也许你可以检查海克力士的盔甲？
perhaps you would care to inspect the armor of Hercules?
皮革盔甲吗？
Leather armor?
嗯？
Mmm?
我们将像猪一样被串起
We will be skewered like pigs.
亚麻胸甲
Linothorax.
从大野猪皮肤的凿成的
Hewn from the skin of the Erymanthean Boar.
这是坚不可摧的
It's indestructible.
等一下如果是坚不可摧的.海克力士是怎么杀掉野猪的？
Wait. If it's indestructible,how did Hercules cut it off the boar?
他使用 一个坚不可摧的刀片
He used an indestructible blade.
一、二
One, two.
起来
Get up.
下一个！
Next!
再来一次！
Again!
睁开双眼
Both eyes open.
继续练习
Keep practicing.
稳中求胜
Firmer grip.
肘部
Elbow up.
好
Good.
盾墙！形式！
Shield wall! Form!
巍然屹立
Stand tall.
太好了
Excellent.
小心你不要砍到自己，男孩
Careful you don't cut yourself, boy.
再次！
Again!
瑞社在这里
Rhesus is here.
足够接近的将刀子砍在他肋骨上
Close enough to stick a blade between his ribs.
你看到了什么？
What did you see?
半人马半人半马 数以百计的他们
Centaurs.Half man, half horse.Hundreds of them.
在夜里他看到阴影
He saw shadows in the night.
我的王，我将率先冲锋到到瑞社阵营
My Lord, I will go ahead into the Rhesus camp.
我会遵照他的计划
I will bring word of his plans.
如果我们让他们穿过了埃蒂克山,色雷斯将会沦陷
If we let them get past Mount Asticus,Thrace will fall.
你想要阻止瑞社吗？
You want to stop Rhesus?
我们穿过森林 他们将不会发现我们的到来
We'll go through the forest and they'll never see us coming.
它会减慢我们的战车的前进 根本就是一场赌博
It'll slow down our chariots. A gamble.
我有一个计划
I have a plan.
斥候兵已经回来了
The scouts have returned.
瑞社把他的阵营驻扎在埃蒂克山，72联盟
Rhesus has made his camp in Mount Asticus,72 leagues away.
一旦这些人准备好了，我们就前进
Once these men are ready, we march.
所以，你有看到我们是赢了还是输了？
So, have you seen if we win or lose?
神已经很厌烦回覆那些小事
The gods have been annoyingly silent on that matter.
但他告诉我
What they have told me is
我很快发现真正的天堂或地狱
that I'm soon to discover...there truly is a heaven or a hell.
你什么时候死？
When will you die?
一周以内地方看起来非常像地狱
Within a week in a place that looks an awful lot like hell.
像往常一样，神总是慷慨的提示
As always, the gods are generous with hints,
但是省略细节
but cheap on specifics.
振作起来，海克力士
Oh, cheer up, Hercules.
我活的，并不好但足够长的时间
I've lived, not always well,but long enough.
我准备好我的下一步了
I'm ready for what's next.
色雷斯人，停止！
Thracians, halt!
盾墙！形式！
Shield wall! Form!
战斗位置！
Battle positions!
堤丢斯？
Tydeus?
这里没有敌人的营地
There is no enemy camp.
这理是正确的地点
This is the right place.
半人马！
Centaurs!
他们是真实的
They're real.
看来如我们所预期
It seems that we're expected.
半人马？
Centaurs?
瑞社！
Rhesus!
你来找人打架的话我们乐意效劳
You have come looking for a fight,and we are happy to oblige.
海克力士宙斯的儿子
Hercules. The son of Zeus.
你的传奇在这里结束
Your legend ends here.
看着我
Look at me.
你有看到我害怕吗？
Do I look afraid?
菲尼亚斯
Phineas.
叛徒！
Traitor!
下地狱吧！
Hades will have you!
在你之后，我的王
After it has you, My Lord.
结束，科蒂王
It is over, Cotys.
埃蒂克在你的面前.树林在你的背部
Mount Asticus on your front.The woods at your back.
和我的部队在数量上超过你三倍
And my troops outman you three to one.
现在投降 我们会考虑对你们仁慈一点
Surrender now, and we shall consider being merciful.
跟我们国王以这种方式说话的都死了
Men die who speak to my lord in such a manner.
这是你自己选择的
You've made your choice.
走吧！
Go!
在这一刻，在这一天
In this moment, on this day,
成为那个人，你出生就已经注定的！
become the man you were born to be!
编写一个包含你们自己在内的自己的传奇！
You have it within yourselves to write your own legends!
让它成为死亡或胜利！
Let it be to death or victory!
进攻！
Charge!
盾墙！
Shield wall!
侧翼出来！
Flanks out!
也许今天
Maybe today.
现在！
Now!
看着亚马逊使用阿耳忒弥斯箭头…
Watch as the Amazon uses the arrows of Artemis...
沉默，男孩！
Silence, boy!
长矛攻击！
Spears forward!
弓箭手，准备好了！
Archers, ready!
放箭！
Loose!
推进！
Advance!
燃烧他们！
Set them aflame!
注意隐蔽！
Take cover!
保卫科蒂王！
Defend Lord Cotys!
也许不是
Maybe not.
盾墙！攻击！
Shield wall! Attack!
推进！
Push forward!
杀死一条蛇，要先切断它的头
To kill a snake, cut off its head.
胜利是你的，科蒂王！
Victory is yours, Lord Cotys!
现在还没有结束！
It is not over yet!
他妈的半人马
Fucking centaurs.
欢呼、科蒂王！欢呼、科蒂王！
Hail, Lord Cotys! Hail, Lord Cotys!
欢呼、科蒂王！
Hail, Lord Cotys!
停止！
Halt!
起来
Get up.
起来 够了！
- Up.- Enough!
你帮助了一个暴君奴役一个国家
You helped a tyrant enslave a nation.
我所做的就是阻止你燃烧更多的村庄
All I did was stop you from burning more villages.
我没有烧毁村庄
I burned no villages.
那是谁干的？
Then who did?
问问你自己 如果科蒂王，至爱的人类
Ask yourself,if Cotys is beloved
为什么他需要雇用雇佣兵做他的脏工作 ？
why did he need to hire mercenaries to do his dirty work?
保持移动，狗
Keep moving, dog.
你一直在帮错误的一边战斗
You've been fighting on the wrong side.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我要带一些水的给囚犯
I'm taking some water to the prisoner.
坐下来
Sit down.
时间到了
It's time.
色雷斯终于统一
Thrace is finally united.
一个土地
One land,
一个国王
one King,
一个色雷斯
one Thrace.
一个土地！
One land!
一个国王！一个色雷斯！
One King! One Thrace!
色雷斯并不是一个人 国王或上帝！
Thrace is not a man, a king,or a god!
色雷斯是她的人！
Thrace is her people!
谁在乎瑞社说什么？我们的工作就完成了
Who cares what Rhesus claims?Our work is done.
让我们拿着费用离开吧
Let's collect our fee and be gone.
不要做任何愚蠢的
Don't do anything foolish.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
我从你的眼睛看到了你为瑞社怜悯
I saw pity in your eyes for Rhesus.
为什么？
Why?
看着我
Look at me.
发起这场战争是科蒂王的责任，不是吗？
Cotys is responsible for this war, isn't he?
你谎说得很好很明显 你是你父亲的女儿
You lie very well. Clearly,your father's daughter.
我这样做不是为了我的父亲 我是为了我的儿子
I didn't do it for my father.I did it for my son.
如果我违反了科蒂或以任何方式反对他 艾利斯将被处决
If I disobeyed Cotys or resisted in any way, Arius would be executed.
我做了母亲 我保护我的孩子
I did what any mother would.I protected my child.
我的丈夫是国王
My husband was king.
科蒂毒害了他来接替他的位置
And Cotys poisoned him to take his place.
瑞社进行反击内战爆发
Rhesus fought back. Civil war broke out.
艾利斯是合法的国王
Arius is the legitimate king.
我的父亲老了
My father is old.
他不会永远活着 一旦他死了
He will not live forever, and once he is gone,
我的儿子将是一个好国王
my son will be a good king.
和他会治疗这块土地
And he will heal this land.
这是一个梦
That's a dream.
你可以帮助
And you can help.
当你离开的时候请色雷斯 带上艾利斯
Please,when you leave Thrace,take Arius with you.
请保证他的安全
Please keep him safe.
找到另一个救世主
Find another savior.
海克力士？
Hercules?
国王命令你过去
The King commands your presence.
我的夫人
My Lady.
啊，色雷斯的冠军！
Ah, champion of Thrace!
听说，我们不会得到报酬
Something tells me we're not gonna get paid.
你可能是正确的! 哦，妈的
- You could be right.- Oh, shit.
你想要的是征服者而不是英雄
You wanted conquerors, not heroes.
科蒂，你背叛了我
You betrayed me, Cotys.
背叛吗？
Betrayed?
一个一直以来的雇佣兵出售他的良心给了黄金
A mercenary who has long since sold his conscience for gold
不能擅自批判他的雇主
can hardly presume to judge his employers.
让我们不要对细节的斤斤计较
Let's not quibble about details.
我们都知道你的传说 海克力士，但这里是我的
We all know your legend, Hercules.But here is mine.
当我还是个将军在色雷斯的军队
When I was a general in the army of Thrace,
我的梦想统治这个王国
I had dreams of ruling this kingdom.
但是谢谢你.我的梦想也越来越大
But thanks to you, my dreams have grown.
我现在渴望一个帝国
I now crave an empire.
我的成千上万军队.培训更多的人，甚至更多
My thousands will train more thousands, and they even more.
海克力士的训练将蔓延
The lessons of Hercules will spread.
什么你在这里开始，永远不能停止
What you began here can never be stopped.
如果你害怕这样的一支军队 可能做出什么可怕的事
And if you fear what such an army may do,
那就过来领导他吧
then lead it.
你想让我为你服务吗？
You want me to serve you?
饶恕我的道德义愤
Spare me the moral outrage.
孩子的杀手
Child killer.
会让我们所有人死亡，坏主意
Getting us all killed, bad idea.
好吧，我必须把这个当作一个“不”
Well, I must take this as a "no."
在这种情况下
In that case,
我不再需要你了
your services are no longer required.
你会全部付清佣金把他们的黄金拿上来
You will be paid in full.Bring them the gold.
如果我们快点，我们可以在马其顿度过我们的未来
If we hurry, we can be spending our fortunes in Macedonia.
也带上我的
Take mine, too.
你怎么了，你认为你是在做什么？ 我们走吧
What do you think you're doing? Let's go.
不会有更多的无辜人 在我的手中牺牲
There will be no more innocent blood on my hands.
在改正这个错误以前 我不能离开
I can't leave without setting this right.
哦，我明白了
Oh, I see.
谁会支付我们这一自杀的行为吗？
And who's gonna be payingus for this suicidal endeavor?
色雷斯需要我们的帮助
Thrace needs our help.
管他的，色雷斯 我们有黄金
To hell with Thrace. We have gold.
你还记得黑海
You remember the Black Sea.
海滩，你提到的，是触手可及 走了，免费的
That beach you spoke of is within reach.Leave now, be free.
我永远不会是免费的
I would never be free.
在这场战斗中，你将独自一人
In this fight, you're alone.
我没看到有人要离开
Never saw that one coming.
你能走开吗？你不能离开
How can you just walk away? You can't just leave.
为什么不呢？好吧
Why not? It's all right.
你已经贡献了你的生命给我 现在你终于可以解脱了
You've sacrificed your lives for me.Now you can finally be free.
您认为什么样的债务 你欠我了
Whatever debt you feel you owe me is paid.
债务？
Debt?
你认为我们追随你 因为我们欠你吗？
You think we follow you because we owe you?
环顾四周，海克力士
Look around, Hercules.
我们是一个家
We're family.
我们有彼此
All we have is each other.
我们将为你而战 如果这是我们的生命的终点，我们将为你而死
We will fight for you. And if it's our time, we will die for you.
因为你也会为我们而死
Because you would die for us.
把这个都拿去吧,我不需要它
Take that, too. I have no need of it.
这是疯狂的
This is madness.
你要疯狂吗？
You want madness?
今晚，一个矛状的火焰将刺穿我的心
Tonight, a spear of flame will pierce my heart.
这是最疯狂的死亡 你听说过吗？
Is that not the most insane death you've ever heard of?
疯了你们都是
Crazy. The lot of you.
奥托吕科斯
Autolycus.
依跟奥托吕科斯走
Iolaus. Go with Autolycus.
我想我会留下来
I think I'll stay.
侄子
Nephew.
叔叔，我所讲过的都是别人的故事
Uncle, all I've ever done is tell stories of great deeds performed by others.
是时候该停止他们的故事了 开始我自己的
It's time I stopped telling their stories.Started living my own.
嗯，你可能有完全失去了你的理智但是我没有
Well, you may have all completely lost your minds, but not me.
不是我
Not me.
奥托吕科斯？
Autolycus?
像国王一样生活，我的朋友
Live like a king, my friend.
要怎么处理科蒂王？
What about Cotys?
他支付我们拯救色雷斯
He paid us to save Thrace.
我们不要让他失望
Let's not disappoint him.
放下你的武器
Lay down your arms.
放下你的武器！
Lay down your arms!
或者你的侄子先死
Or your nephew dies first.
我邀请你加入我 你拒绝
I invite you to join me. You refuse.
我命令你离开 你回来了
I order you to leave. You return.
把你的手从我身上拿开
Get your hands off me.
我听到她与海克力士阴谋
I overheard her conspiring with Hercules.
他们打算移除你对王子的保护
They were planning to remove the young Prince from your protection.
不
No.
放开他！不要碰他！
Let go of him! Don't touch him!
艾利斯！不！
Arius! No!
不！你会伤到他！不！
No! You're hurting him! No!
赫拉克勒斯，不！帮帮我！停止！
Hercules, no! Help me! Stop!
- 救命！不！ - 艾利斯不
- Help! No! - Arius. No.
艾利斯！不！
Arius! No!
华丽吧，不是吗？
Magnificent, aren't they?
一个非凡的物种令人难以置信的忠诚
An extraordinary species.Incredibly loyal.
只要他们被喂食
As long as they're fed.
还记得他们吗？三头狗
- Remember them? - Eurystheus.
他们还记得你
They remember you.
困惑？海克力士
Confused, Hercules?
王国是靠军队赢得,但帝国是由联盟而得
Kingdoms are won with armies,but empires are made by alliances.
三头狗和我现在将统治希腊
King Eurystheus and I will now rule all of Greece.
三头狗只存在于我的脑海里
Cerberus only exists in my mind.
说大声一点,海克力士
Speak a little louder, Hercules.
我听不清
I didn't quite catch that.
那狼
The wolves.
那天晚上他们在那里
They were there that night.
那狼
The wolves were there.
你下药害我
You drugged me.
有狼,那晚我家人是被谋杀的
The wolves were there the night my family was murdered.
我的人告诉我你的孩子如何尖叫
My men told me how your children screamed
正如我的狼咬骨头
as my wolves gnawed on their bones.
作为他们的尖牙夺走你的女儿的
As their fangs despoiled your daughter's...
纯粹的肉体
pure flesh.
当人们喊出你的名字比我的名字大声
When the people called out your name louder than mine,
你看，当他们看到你作为一个上帝
you see, when they saw
多久之前他们认为你是他们的王？
you as a god, how long...you see, when they saw before they saw you as their king?
我什么都不要！
I wanted nothing!
精确的说！你的错误在于你没有野心！海克力士
Precisely! Your sin, Hercules,was that you had no ambition!
我能对付一个雄心勃勃的人！他可以被收买！
I can deal with an ambitious man!He can be bought!
但一个人什么都不想要 没有价格！
But a man who wants nothing has no price!
杀死你会让雅典转而攻击我
Killing you would have turned Athens against me.
我要毁了你的名字
I had to ruin your name.
我的妻子！
My wife!
我的孩子们！
My children!
嗯，你有我的许可加入他们的死亡
Well, you have our permission to join them in death.
你们所有的人！ 从我不忠实的女儿开始！
All of you! Starting with my faithless daughter!
不！放开我！
No! Get off me!
不！不！不！
No! No! No!
放掉我！不！
Unhand me! No!
她是你的血肉！
She's your own flesh and blood!
我将提升艾利斯为我值得的接班人！
I will raise Arius to be my worthy successor!
你远离我的男孩！你的怪物，你这个混蛋！
You stay away from my boy!You monster, you bastard!
你是一个怪物！你是一个怪物！ 不！
You are a monster!You are a monster! No!
你不是一个男人！
You are not a man!
你是一个恶魔！
You're a demon!
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是杀人犯吗？
Are you a murderer?
该死的你！我诅咒你！
Damn you! I curse you!
你是在做为一个背叛无辜牺牲者的人的雇佣兵吗？
Are you a mercenary who turns his back on the innocent?
远离我的儿子！
Stay away from my son!
你只有传说吗？
Are you only the legend？
或者你是传说背后的真相？
Or are you the truth behind the legend?
不！父亲.不要，不要
No! Father, please, please, please.
我们相信你
We believe in you.
我们对你有信心
We have faith in you.
对自己有信心
Have faith in yourself.
救我！
Save me!
还记得那个人 那是你
Remember the man that you are.
父亲，神会惩罚你的！这次你不能逃避！
Father, the gods will punish you!You cannot escape this time!
记住这行为,你的表现
Remember the deeds you have performed,
你的考验已经完成了！
the Labors you have accomplished!
不！不！
No! No!
停止它！绝不能她一个人！
Stop it! - Leave her alone!
现在，告诉我！
Now, tell me!
拜托！
Please!
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是海克力士！
I am Hercules!
释放狼！
Unleash the wolves!
离开！
Get away!
啊
Ahh!
三狼应该是比一只狮子厉害
Three wolves should be more than enough for one lion.
啊
快点！
Hurry!
快点！快点！
Hurry!  Hurry!
不！
No!
啊
Ahh!
众神都见证你的清白
The gods have revealed your innocence.
最后的考验已经完成了
The final Labor is complete.
但是我才刚刚要开始
But I'm just getting started.
我不想知道在上面等待我们的是什么了
Doesn't take a vision to know what's waiting for us up there.
我的时候到了
My time.
抱歉这是我的时刻，我的命运
Excuse me. That was my moment, my fate.
不客气
You're welcome.
我要欧律斯透斯！
I'm going after Eurystheus!
海克力士，听我说这一切都是我的错
Hercules, listen to me.None of this is my fault.
你看科蒂王毒害我的脑袋
You see, Cotys poisoned my mind.
让我对抗你
Turned me against you.
我喜欢你
I like you.
不，停止
No, stop.
我命令你停止！ 我是你的国王！你宣誓服从我！
I command you to stop! I'm your King!You took an oath to obey me!
你向宙斯发誓的！
You swore to Zeus!
等待，等待，等待
Wait, wait, wait.
你为金币而战我有很多金子依您的价格
You fight for gold. I have plenty of gold. Name your price.
得到它，让心去宽恕
Find it in your heart to forgive.
你要被宽恕吗？
You want forgiveness?
要求我的家人原谅吧
Ask my family for forgiveness.
我从来没有杀了一个神
I've never killed a god before.
我真的认为我现在准备好战斗了
I really think I'm ready to fight now.
干得好，战士
Well done, warrior.
欧律斯透斯？ 死
Eurystheus? - Dead.
我们需要找到艾利斯 跟我来
We need to find Arius. - Follow me.
色雷斯的士兵！
Soldiers of Thrace!
在战斗中你们跟随我,现在再次跟随我吧
You followed me in battle.Follow me now.
别傻瓜！
Don't be fools!
海克力士是凡人！不是神！
Hercules is mortal! Not a god！
任何跟随他的人都会死！
Anyone who sides with him will die!
我将向您展示
And I will show you.
带他来
Bring him.
艾利斯！妈妈！
Arius! - Mama!
不！他是你的孙子！
No! He's your grandson!
你没有保护好你的孩子，海克力士
You failed to save your children, Hercules.
但你可能会救他
But you may yet save him.
请父亲！不！
Please, Father! No!
承认失败
Admit defeat!
屈服于我！
Bow to me!
数到三！
You have until the count of three!
一！
One!
二！
Two!
不要只是站在那儿！杀了他们！
Don't just stand there! Kill someone!
保护科蒂王！
Protect Lord Cotys!
艾利斯，快跑！
Arius, run!
妈妈！
Mother!
抓住男孩！
Get the boy!
啊
堤丢斯！
Tydeus!
攻击！
Attack!
牵制他们！
Hold them back!
长矛！
Spears!
穿过火！
Go through the fire!
在这里！在这里！的帮助！来吧！
Here! Here! Help! Come on!
放轻松，堤丢斯
Easy, Tydeus.
海克力士
Hercules.
锁盾牌！
Lock shields!
前进！
March!
安详的去吧，我的兄弟
Find peace, my brother.
正如你说，海克力士.没有人能够打败一个盾墙！
As you said, Hercules, there is no way to defeat a shield wall!
没有出路！
There is no way out!
出来面对我！
Come out and face me!
你不是英雄！你不是上帝！
You're no hero! You're no god!
你什么都不是，只是一个雇佣兵！
You're nothing but a mercenary!
你的妻子和孩子应该被处死！
Your wife and children deserved to die!
你做什么？
What're you doing?
回来了！
Get back up there!
海克力士必须死！
Hercules must die!
来吧！
Come on!
杀了那个卑劣的混蛋！
Kill that filthy bastard!
海克力士！海克力士！
Hercules! Hercules!
你想知道关于海克力士的真相？
You want to know the truth about Hercules?
这就是了
There it is.
说实话，我喜欢传奇
To be honest, I prefer it to the legend.
世界需要英雄 他们可以被相信
The world needs a hero they can believe in.
他真的是宙斯的儿子？
Is he actually the son of Zeus?
我不认为这真的很重要
I don't think it really matters.
你不需要半神英雄
You don't need to be a demigod to be a hero.
你只需要相信你是个英雄
You just need to believe you're a hero.
这样来说就足够了
It's what worked for him.
但话又说回来,我到底能预知什么？
But then again,what the hell do I know?
我现在应该是死了才对
I'm supposed to be dead by now.